Martino Mensio

BACKGROUND

email: martino.mensio@open.ac.uk

linkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/martinomensio/

website: https://martinomensio.github.io/

I am currently a Research Assistant at Knowledge Media Institute (The Open University, UK) working on Deep Learning for Natural Language Understanding. My background in Software Engineering comes from the studies carried in Politecnico di Torino where I achieved both the Bachelor's and Master's degrees.

For the near future I would like to stay in research, possibly starting with a PhD. My interests focus on Conversational Agents, Text Processing, Deep Learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MAY 2018-Current Research Assistant at Knowledge Media Institute, The Open University, UK

I am working in a team that is focused on robotics. The goal is to build a prototype of a robot that combines different abilities in order to provide a *office assistant* capable of moving around and perform actions on command. My role is to provide a Natural Language Interface for the robot in order to enable a simple

conversation with it.

MAR 2017-MAR 2018 Master's thesis project at ISTITUTO SUPERIORE MARIO BOELLA, Torino

Deep Semantic Learning for Conversational Agents

The goals of this research thesis are of two different natures: *i*) analyze the State of the Art in order to identify the approaches that better suit the creation of a Conversational Agent (Natural Language Understanding) *ii*)

build a bot prototype that uses the selected approaches.

MAR-SEP 2015 Internship at Scloby SRL, Torino

End-to-End testing and development for an AngularJS application

In the first part of the internship I wrote end-to-end tests using Protractor (a framework to do automatic tests on AngularJS apps). The tests simulated the user interactions and checked the correct behaviour of the application. During the second part I moved to the development activity. Using AngularJS I implemented

some functionalities of the app. I wrote some controllers, templates and directives.

EDUCATION

APRIL 2018 Master's Degree in Computer Engineering

Politecnico di Torino, Major: Software, 110L/110 GPA: 29.93/30 | Detailed List of Exams at page 3

DECEMBER 2015 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

Politecnico di Torino, 109/110

GPA: 28,66/30 Detailed List of Exams at page 3

SUMMER 2012 Scientific High School Diploma

Liceo Scientifico "G.B. Bodoni", Saluzzo, 92/100

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, Arch), Windows (7/8/10)

Programming Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP

Databases: Relational (Oracle/SQLite/PostgreSQL) and non-relational (MongoDB)

Web: Spring, AngularJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Flask

Machine Learning: Artificial Neural Networks, Deep Learning, Recurrent Neural Networks,

Word Embeddings, TensorFlow, Keras, SpaCy NLP

Others: Office suites (Microsoft Office, LibreOffice),

IDE (Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Visual Studio, codeblocks)

PUBLICATIONS

April 2018: Mensio M., Rizzo G., Morisio M. "Multi-turn QA: A RNN Contextual Approach to Intent Clas-

sification for Goal-oriented Systems." In (WWW) 1st International Workshop on Hybrid Question

Answering with Structured and Unstructured Knowledge (HQA) Lyon, France

April 2018: Mensio M., Rizzo G., Morisio M. "The Rise of Emotion-aware Conversational Agents: Threats in

Digital Emotions." In (WWW) Re-coding Black Mirror Lyon, France

SCOLARSHIPS

from 2013 to 2017: Winner of yearly scolarship provided by EDISU Piemonte to univeristy students

Master's Degree in Computer Engineering

Grades

Exam	CREDITS	Grade
Computer architectures	10	30 cum laude
Database management systems	8	30 cum laude
Optimization methods and algorithms	6	30
Computer network technologies and services	6	29
Distributed programming I	6	30 cum laude
Software engineering	8	30
System and device programming	10	30 cum laude
Formal languages and compilers	6	30 cum laude
Distributed programming II	6	30 cum laude
Computer system security	6	30 cum laude
Information systems	6	30
Projects and laboratory on communication systems	6	30 cum laude
Internet applications	6	30 cum laude
	GPA	29.93

Bachelor's Degree in COMPUTER ENGINEERING Grades

Exam	CREDITS	GRADE
Mathematical analysis I	10	24
English Language 1st level	3	passed
Chemistry	8	25
Digital revolution	6	28
Computer science	8	30
Geometry	10	28
Physics I	10	28
Physics II	6	27
Introduction to electrical engineering	10	30 cum laude
Algorithms and Programming	10	30 cum laude
Mathematical analysis II	8	27
Computer systems	8	30 cum laude
Mathematical methods for engineers	10	28
Systems and electronic technologies	10	28
Computer networks	8	30 cum laude
Final essay	1	30 cum laude
Operating systems	6	27
Signal theory and Signal processing	10	26
Object-oriented programming	6	30 cum laude
Automatic control	10	24
Database	6	30 cum laude
Applied Electronics and Measurement	10	30
Professional Training	10	passed
	GPA	28.66